Finding Aid for Frank and Peggy Bach Papers, 1964-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Professional Ventures
  - Aardvark Printing
    Aardvark Printing is one folder of finished product advertising materials mainly for Detroit community organizations and individuals.
    - General 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Grande Graphics
    Grande Graphics is mostly event flyers for groups and concert venues. It also includes some magazine publications and publicity for Detroit-area companies.
    - B'Stilla, Detroit 1983-1986 (Box 2)
    - Clutch Cargo's Productions (Box 2)
    - Cobb's Corner 1983 (Box 2)
    - Goodtime Bar, Livonia 1982-1986 (Box 2)
    - Internal Files 1983 (Box 2)
    - Jefferson-Chalmers Concerts by the River 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - MarketPlace Magazine, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Maximus & Co. Booksellers 1982-1983 (Box 2)
    - Musicians Referral Service 1984 (Box 2)
    - North Cass Street Fair: Dally in the Alley 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Pam Productions 1984 (Box 2)
    - Record Profile Magazine(R.P.M.), 1983 (Box 2)
    - Rock Mill Records 1984 (Box 2)
    - Rockabilly Cats 1984 (Box 2)
    - Rocket Reproductions (Box 2)
    - Rough Cut 1984 (Box 2)
  - Morda-Sinclair & Associates/Media Services Associates/Music Services Associates
    Media Services Associates/Music Services Associates/ Morda-Sinclair and Associates (MSA) is arranged in categories to more clearly identify the materials. Artists includes flyers, publicity, press releases, and article reprints about bands and individual artists. Most of the artists are pop bands although some blues and jazz acts are represented. The files contain comprehensive information about The Flying Tigers, John Sinclair, The Sun Messengers, and The Urbations. Events and Venues mainly consist of flyers. The Internal records hold contracts, press releases, publicity materials, and flyers advertising MSA-related concerts. Projects contains advertising for Detroit-area companies and non-profit groups.
    - Artists
      - Fabulous Checkers (Box 2)
      - Flying Tigers 1982-1984 (Box 2)
      - The Heat/The Intruders 1985 (Box 2)
      - Juanita McCray 1983 (Box 2)
      - Robert Noll and His Blues Mission 1985 (Box 2)
      - The Shy 1984 (Box 2)
      - Nina Simone (Box 2)
      - John Sinclair
        - Flyers 1984-1991 (Box 2)
        - Thelonius: a Book of Monk, Volume 1 1988 (Box 2)
        - We Just Change the Beat 1988 (Box 2)
      - Sun Messengers 1982-1989 (Box 3)
      - Urbations
        - Article Reprints (Box 3)
        - Flyers (Box 3)
        - Promotion 1987 (Box 3)
        - Publicity (chronological) 1982-1987, 5 folders (Box 3)
          see also oversized folder UAl
      - Willie D. Warren 1983-1985 (Box 3)
      - What If Thinking (Box 3)
    - Events
      - Budweiser Motor City Music Fest 1988-1992 (Box 3)
      - Chene Park Summer Arts Festival 1985-1987 (Box 3)
      - Jazz for Life: a Concert to Help Kids 1987 (Box 3)
    - Internal Files
      - Concerts (Box 3)
      - Contract and Forms (Box 3)
      - Press Releases (Box 3)
      - Publicity
        - Media Services Associates (Box 3)
        - Monda/Sinclair & Associates (Box 3)
    - Projects
      - Aztec Staging Company, Ann Arbor (Box 3)
      - Detroit Council of the Arts 1989 (collected) (Box 3)
      - Detroit Recreation Department: Detroit for Africa (Box 3)
      - Du Mouchelles Antiques and Art 1987 (Box 3)
      - Enchanté/Anne René Designs 1986 (Box 3)
      - Metro America Records 1983-1986 (Box 3)
      - Motor City Television Corporation (MCTV) 1986 (Box 3)
      - Music to Save Indigenous Culture (Box 3)
    - Venues
      - Alvin's, Detroit (Box 3)
      - Danceteria, Canton 1985 (Box 3)
      - Hart Plaza (Box 3)
      - Kicks, Detroit 1984-1985 (Box 3)
      - Mr. Christian's, Royal Oak 1985 (Box 3)
      - Music Hall Center for the Performing Arts 1986 (Box 3)
      - Rossi's on the Park, Detroit (Box 3)
      - St. Andrew's Hall, Detroit (Box 3)
      - The Soup Kitchen, Detroit (Box 3)
      - Sully's, Dearborn 1984-1985 (Box 3)
      - The 3 of Us Lounge, Detroit 1984 (Box 3)
      - Traxx, Detroit 1985 (Box 3)
  - The Publications Company
    The Publications Company consists of one folder that includes finished publicity products, mainly in the form of annual reports and other serial publications for local companies and auto manufacturers.
    - General 1989 (Box 3)
  - Bach and Associates
    Bach and Associates is mostly samples of advertisements created for Detroit music and theater organizations. There is also one folder that contains materials related to a project to release a recording of the 1973 Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival.
    - 1973 Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival CD Project, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Blues Advertisements 1990-1994 (Box 3)
    - Chene Park Ads 1991-1993 (Box 3)
    - City Arts Gallery Publicity 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - Fisher Theater Productions 1991-1996 (Box 3)
- Detroit Redevelopment
  The Detroit Redevelopment series (1991-2003, 2.5 lin. ft.) reflects Frank Bach's involvement in community organizations working to revitalize the city of Detroit. The subseries include: Concerts By The River, Coordinating Council on Community Redevelopment, Creekside Community Development Corporation, Jefferson-Chalmers Citizens' District Council, and Jefferson East Business Association.
  - Concerts By The River (CBTR)
    Concerts By The River is an annual series of free outdoor jazz concerts put on by community organizations. This subseries includes concert programs, publicity, production, and financial information.
    - Programs 1979-2000 (Box 3)
    - 1994 Concert Series (Box 3)
    - 1995 Concert Series
      - Financial (Box 3)
      - Production (Box 3)
    - 1996 Concert Series
      - City Arts Grant (Box 3)
      - Production (Box 3)
    - 2000 Concert Series (Box 3)
    - 2001 Concert Series (Box 3)
  - Coordinating Council on Community Redevelopment (CCCR)
    The Coordinating Council on Community Redevelopment brings together representatives from each Citizens' District Council for the purpose of discussing development issues in common. This consists of two folders of correspondence and meeting minutes and reports.
    - Correspondence 1995-1998 (Box 4)
    - Meetings and Reports 1994-1998 (Box 4)
  - Creekside Community Development Corporation (CCDC)
    The Creekside Development Corporation is a grassroots organization created to help facilitate development in the Creekside neighborhood. It was designed to serve as a voice for current residents. The subseries consists of information on development activities, fundraising, meeting minutes and reports, newsletters, and general organizational reference materials.
    - Bach Urban Studies Internship 2000 (Box 4)
    - Board Member Orientation Package 1995 (Box 4)
    - Bylaws 1993-2001 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence 1993-2002 (Box 4)
    - Creekside Home Repair 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - Creekside Resident Survey 1999-2000 (Box 4)
    - Detroit 300 Award 2001 (Box 4)
    - Detroit Eastside Community Collaborative 1995-1997 (Box 4)
    - Fox Creek Sewage Overflow 1995 (Box 4)
    - Fundraising and Grants 1995-2003 (Box 4)
    - Habitat for Humanity Partnership 1997-1999 (Box 4)
    - Meetings and Reports
      - 1995-1996 (Box 4)
      - 1997 (Box 4)
      - 2000-2001 (Box 4)
      - 2002 (Box 4)
    - Michigan State Housing Development Authority (MSHDA) Technical Assistance 2000, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Newsletters
      - 1993-1996 (Box 4)
      - 1997-2002 (Box 4)
    - Program in Legal Assistance for Urban Communities 1995-1996, 2000 (Box 4)
    - Strategic Planning 1995-1996, 2001-2003 (Box 4)
  - Jefferson-Chalmers Citizens' District Council (JCCDC)
    The Jefferson-Chalmers Citizens' District Council is the largest subseries. This is a State-mandated organization charged to approve development projects in the Jefferson-Chalmers area. Materials include information on development projects, financial information, general organizational materials, documents reflecting Frank Bach's many clashes with other members regarding controversial activities and legal matters, meeting information packets, newsletters, and personnel matters.
    - Development
      - Averhill Park 1997 (Box 4)
      - Development Committee 1996-2000 (Box 4)
      - Grayhaven Island/Marina 1985-2001 (Box 4)
      - Jefferson Towne Square 1999-2001 (Box 4)
      - Maheras Park 1993-1997 (Box 4)
      - Modification of Redevelopment Plan 1999-2001 (Box 4)
      - Riverbend Plaza 1994 (Box 4)
    - Financial
      - Budget Committee 1993-2000 (Box 4)
      - Community Development Block Grant Proposal
        - 1997 (Box 4)
        - 1998 (Box 4)
      - Monthly Budget Reports 1994-1997 (Box 4)
    - General
      - Bach Correspondence regarding JCCDC
        - 1993-1996 (Box 4)
        - 1998-2003 (Box 4)
      - Bach Published Writings 1994-1999 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence 1991-2002 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence with Detroit Planning and Development Department (P&DD) 1994-2002 (Box 4)
      - Elections 1994-2000 (Box 4)
      - Event Flyers and Brochures 1995-1998 (Box 4)
      - Jefferson-Chalmers Reference undated (Box 4)
      - Member Education Seminar 1998 (Box 5)
      - Member Orientation Packet 1994 (Box 5)
      - Participation Agreement (JCCDC contract with the City of Detroit)
        - 1994/95 (Box 5)
        - 1997/98 (Box 5)
      - Strategic Plan 1998 (Box 5)
    - Legal/Controversy
      - Administrator Complaints 1995 (Box 5)
      - Administrator Debarment 1993-1995 (Box 5)
      - Averhill Park Grant Fund 1998 (Box 5)
      - Bach Complaints about the JCCDC 1994-2000 (Box 5)
      - Bach Deposition regarding Chambliss v. Walker 1998 (Box 5)
      - Bach Embezzlement Accusation 1995-1996 (Box 5)
      - Bach Michigan Open Meetings Act lawsuit against members of the JCCDC 1995-1997 (Box 5)
      - Bach Removal as Secretary 1995 (Box 5)
      - Citizen Complaints 1994-1995 (Box 5)
      - Complaints to Detroit Planning and Development Department (P&DD) 1994-2000 (Box 5)
      - Conflict of Interest 1994-1997 (Box 5)
      - Improper Meeting Conduct 1994-1999 (Box 5)
      - Police Report 1995 (Box 5)
      - Racial Slurs 1995 (Box 5)
      - Recording of Meetings 1995-1996 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Information Packets
      - July 1993-August, 1994 (Box 5)
      - September-December, 1994 (Box 5)
      - January-June, 1995 (Box 5)
      - July-December, 1995 (Box 5)
      - January-June, 1996 (Box 5)
      - July-December, 1996 (Box 5)
      - January-July, 1997 (Box 5)
      - August-December, 1997 (Box 5)
      - January-June, 1998 (Box 5)
      - July-December, 1998 (Box 5)
      - January-June, 1999 (Box 5)
      - July-December, 1999 (Box 5)
      - January-May 2000 (Box 5)
      - June-October, 2000 (Box 5)
      - 2001 (Box 5)
      - 2002 (Box 5)
    - Newsletters
      - 1983-1993 (Box 5)
      - 1994-2000 (Box 5)
      - Newsletter Production 1994-1996 (Box 5)
    - Personnel
      - Employee Manuals and Job Descriptions 1985-1998 (Box 6)
      - Personnel Committee
        - 1992-September 1997 (Box 6)
        - October 1997-2000 (Box 6)
  - Jefferson East Business Association (JEBA)
    The Jefferson East Business Association is an organization made up of business owners in the Jefferson-Chalmers area. It works to promote economic growth in the area. The subseries consists of correspondence, bylaws, meeting minutes, marketing activities, newsletters, and fundraising materials.
    - Bylaws and Organization 1995, undated (Box 6)
    - Correspondence 1993-1998 (Box 6)
    - Marketing/PR 1993-1994, undated (Box 6)
    - Meeting Minutes 1993-2002 (Box 6)
    - Newsletters 1994-2001 (Box 6)
    - Projects and Grants 1993-1994 (Box 6)
- Arts and Culture
  The Arts and Culture series (1988-1999, 0.3 lin. ft.) consists of materials documenting the Detroit Arts scene. Organizations promoting blues and jazz, creative writing, and artwork are represented. Also a part of this series are materials related to the creative activities of John Sinclair, including some writings, radio show transcripts, and draft scripts of the film "Twenty to Life."
  - Alternative Press undated (Box 6)
  - Blues Review 1993-1996 (scattered) (Box 6)
  - Detroit Blues Society Publications and Press Releases 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - John Sinclair
    - Radio Shows and Tours 1988-1995 (Box 6)
    - "Twenty to Life" Film Scripts 1995-1997 (Box 6)
    - Writings and Correspondence 1985-1999 (Box 6)
  - Leni Sinclair Artwork 1993-1994 (Box 6)
  - Straits, Creative Writing Newsletter of the Detroit River Press 1982-1984 (scattered) (Box 6)
- Newspaper Clippings
  The Newspaper Clippings series (1966-2000, 0.4 lin. ft.) contains articles collected or written by the Bachs. Arranged by subject matter, they include political activity, concerts and productions, reports involving personal friends, and articles regarding their personal and professional activities.
  - Articles written by Frank Bach 1977 (Box 6)
  - Artists' Workshop 1980 (Box 6)
  - Blues and Jazz Festivals 1972-1974 (Box 6)
  - Detroit Jazz Center 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Detroit Redevelopment
    - Citizens' District Council Controversies 1995-2000 (Box 6)
    - Development Projects and Events 1994-2000 (Box 6)
    - Fox Creek Sewage Overflow 1994-1996 (Box 6)
    - Jefferson East Business Association (JEBA) 1993-1995 (Box 6)
    - Maheras Park 1964-1996 (Box 6)
  - Grande Ballroom 1966-1970 (Box 6)
  - John Sinclair 1967-1989 (Box 6)
  - Social and Political Activities 1967-1989 (Box 6)
  - The UP 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - The Urbations (Box 6)
- Visual Materials
  The majority of the Visual Materials series (1965-1995, 2.3 lin. ft.) consists of artists' and musicians' photographs assembled with the intent of using the images for publicity purposes. It includes concert photographs, candid images, and a few promotional shots. The series contains mainly Michigan-based jazz, blues, and pop artists although it also represents national and international musicians. Artists either associated with Strata Corporation, MSA, or the Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festivals typically have the most images. Many of the photographs were taken by Leni Sinclair. This series also contains film reels showing the Contemporary Jazz Quintet Concert at the 1972 Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival. Also included are posters, album covers, and miscellaneous other publicity.
  - Drawings
    - Psychedelic Drugs (Box 6)
    - John Sinclair (Box 6)
  - Photographs
    - Luther Allison (Box 6)
    - Peter Andrews (Box 6)
    - Johnny Angelos' Reputations (Box 6)
    - Ann Arbor Bands (Box 6)
    - Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival
      (see also individual bands/musicians and the Crowd Pictures folder)
      - Concerts (Box 6)
      - Publicity Images (Box 6)
    - Art Ensemble of Chicago (Box 7)
    - A. Spencer Barefield 1979 (Box 7)
    - Count Basie (Box 7)
    - Jonnie Bassett (Box 7)
    - Flash Beaver 1978 (Box 7)
    - Marcus Belgrave (Box 7)
    - Norma Bell (Box 7)
    - James Blanchard Shish Ke Bash 1987 (includes Coleman Young) (Box 7)
    - Bobby "Blue" Bland (Box 7)
    - Blue Magic (Box 7)
    - Blue Notes, Detroit Blues Society (includes Larry Brown, Bobby East, Jeff Grand, Johnny "Yard Dog" Jones, Robert Jones, Lazy Lester, Jimmy McCarty, Larry McCray, Lloyd Parks, Teddy Pendergrass, Arthur Penhallow, Willie D. Warren and Bernie Wilson) (Box 7)
    - Blues (includes Louisiana Red, Magic Sam, Bessie Smith, and Mose Allison) (Box 7)
    - Jack Brokensha (Box 7)
    - Brooklyn Blues Busters (Box 7)
    - Roy Brooks (Box 7)
    - James Brown (Box 7)
    - Perry Bullard 1973 (Box 7)
    - Eddie "Guitar" Burns, circa 1982 (includes Eddie Kirkland and Little Sonny) (Box 7)
      (see also Detroit Blues)
    - Donald Byrd (Box 7)
    - CJQ (Box 7)
    - Cab Calloway 1978 (Box 7)
    - Little Junior Cannady (Box 7)
    - Ray Charles (Box 7)
    - Chene Park, Detroit (Box 7)
    - Chicago Blues (includes Andrew "Blueblood" McMahon, Sunnyland Slim, Jimmy Dawkins, Carey Bell, Homesick James, Junior Wells, Otis Rush, and Lefty Diaz) (Box 7)
    - Cobb's Corner (Box 7)
    - Concerts By The River (CBTR) 1994-1996 (Box 7)
    - Johnny Copeland, circa 1970s-1993 (Box 7)
    - Bill Cosby (Box 7)
    - James Cotton Band (Box 7)
    - Creative Arts Collective (Box 7)
    - Crowd Pictures (mainly Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festivals) (Box 7)
    - Tim Cunningham (Box 7)
    - George Cushingberry, Jr. (Box 7)
    - Dancers (Box 7)
    - Clive Davis (includes Alan Parsons) (Box 7)
    - Eddie "Lockjaw" Davis (Box 7)
    - Miles Davis (Box 7)
    - Richard Davis (Box 7)
    - Thornetta Davis (Box 7)
    - Tyrone Davis (Box 7)
    - Jimmy Dawkins (Box 7)
      (see also Chicago Blues)
    - Deano Day (Box 7)
    - Jack DeJohnette (Box 7)
    - The Dells (Box 7)
    - Detroit
      - Blues (includes Otis Clay, Little Junior Cannady, Eddie Burns, and Lightnin' Slim) (Box 7)
      - City Council (Box 7)
      - General City Scenes (Box 7)
      - Jazz (includes Beans Bowles, Rod Hicks, and Jack Brokensha) (Box 7)
      - Police (Box 7)
      - Political (Box 7)
      - Schools (Box 7)
      - Sports (Box 7)
    - Detroit Blues Band (Box 7)
    - Detroit Emeralds (Box 7)
    - Detroit Jazz Artists on Tour 1974 (Box 7)
    - Bo Diddley (Box 7)
    - Willie Dixon 1972 (Box 7)
    - Domino (Box 7)
    - Fats Domino 1977 (Box 7)
    - Lucky Dube (Box 7)
    - George Duke (Box 7)
    - Stanley "Buckwheat" Dural (Box 7)
    - Bob Dylan (Box 7)
    - Mercer Ellington (Box 7)
    - Leroy Emmanual (Box 7)
    - Ron English (Box 7)
    - Eli Ervin (Box 7)
    - The Bill Evans Trio (Box 7)
    - Clifford Fears (Box 7)
    - Zolton Ferency (Box 7)
    - Fito (Box 7)
    - The Flying Tigers (Box 7)
    - The Four Tops (Box 7)
    - Carolyn and Aretha Franklin (Box 7)
    - Sonny Freeman and the Unusuals (Box 7)
    - Kenny Garrett (Box 7)
    - Jimmy Garrison (Box 7)
    - Marvin Gaye (Box 7)
    - Dizzy Gillespie (Box 7)
    - Allen Ginsberg 1971-1974 (Box 7)
    - George Goldsmith (Box 7)
    - John Granoplis (Box 7)
    - Johnny Griffin (Box 7)
    - Griot Galaxy (Box 7)
    - Arthur Gunter (Box 7)
    - Buddy Guy (with Junior Wells) (Box 7)
    - Charlie Haden (Box 7)
    - Nasir Hafiz 1978 (Box 7)
    - Pancho Hagood (Box 7)
    - LaMonte Hamilton 1979-1980 (Box 7)
    - Herbie Hancock (Box 7)
    - Sir Roland Hanna (Box 7)
    - Wendell Harrison (Box 7)
      (see also Jazz folder)
    - Hart Plaza, Detroit (Box 7)
    - Hastings Street Jazz Experience (Box 7)
    - Woody Herman (Box 7)
    - Mike Holbrook 1978 (Box 7)
    - Doc Holladay (Box 7)
    - Dave Holland (Box 7)
    - David S. Holmes 1979 (Box 7)
    - John Lee Hooker (Box 7)
    - Linda Hopkins 1977 (Box 7)
    - Big Walter Horton (Box 7)
    - Al Hudson (Box 7)
    - J.B. Hutto (Box 7)
    - Ken Ingraham 1980 (Box 7)
    - Isley Brothers (Box 7)
    - Ron Jackson (Box 7)
    - Leno Jackson (Box 7)
    - Jazz (includes Nina Simone, Burton Green, Joseph Jarman, Charles Clark, Betty Carter, Amad Jamal, Rashid Ali, Richard Wright, Sonny Redd, Thad Jones, Mel Lewis, Kenny Burrell, and Lewis Smith) (Box 7)
    - Jazz Center Conference (Box 7)
    - Jazz Research Institute Exhibition 1979 (Box 7)
    - Eddie Jefferson (Box 7)
    - Bobo Jenkins (Box 7)
    - Dr. John (Box 7)
    - Candy Johnson 1978 (Box 7)
    - Mark Johnson 1980 (Box 7)
    - Elvin Jones (Box 7)
    - Johnny "Yard Dog" Jones 1993 (Box 7)
      (see also Blue Notes folder)
    - Sundiata Keita 1980 (Box 7)
    - Eddie Kendricks (Box 7)
    - Little Junior Kennedy 1971 (Box 7)
    - Kamau Kenyata 1980 (Box 7)
    - Albert and B.B. King (Box 7)
    - Freddie King (Box 7)
    - Leonard King (Box 7)
    - Gladys Knight (Box 7)
    - Wayne Kramer (Box 7)
    - Oliver Lake 1993 (Box 7)
    - Yusef Lateef (Box 7)
    - Let's Talk About Girls (Box 7)
    - George Lewis (Box 7)
    - Ramsey Lewis (Box 7)
    - Lightnin' Slim (Box 7)
    - Mance Lipscomb (Box 7)
    - Little Sonny, circa 1960s-1981 (Box 7)
      see also Eddie Burns folder
    - Robert Junior Lockwood (Box 7)
    - Robert Lowe, Jr. (Box 7)
    - MSFB (Box 7)
    - Joe Madison (Box 7)
    - Taj Mahal (Box 7)
    - The Mandingo Griot Society (Box 7)
    - Bob Marley (Box 7)
    - LaVerna Mason (Box 7)
    - Johnnie Mae Matthews 1973 (Box 7)
    - Bernie Maupin 1981 (Box 7)
    - Les McCann (Box 7)
    - Juanita McCray 1982 (Box 7)
    - Malvin McCray (Box 7)
    - Mississippi Fred McDowell (Box 7)
    - Freddy McGregor 1981 (Box 7)
    - Harold McKinney (Box 8)
    - John McLaughlin 1975 (Box 8)
    - David McMurray 1982 (Box 8)
    - Ronnie McNeir (Box 8)
      (see also Motown folder)
    - Media Services Associates (Box 8)
    - Johnny Metcalf 1980 (Box 8)
    - Sue Michaels (Box 8)
    - Midnight Sky 1982 (Box 8)
    - Military (Box 8)
    - Ron Milner (Box 8)
    - Mime (Box 8)
    - Charles Mingus (Box 8)
    - Mr. Bo (Box 8)
    - Mixed Bag (Box 8)
    - Charles Moore 1974 (Box 8)
    - Motown (includes Ronnie McNeir, Marvin Gaye, Motown Buildings, Leon Ware, the Gordy Family, and G.C. Cameron) (Box 8)
    - Music Hall (Box 8)
    - Musical Acts (includes Joe Simon, Nadine Brown, William Bell, Al Hudson, and David Bromberg) (Box 8)
    - Ralph Nader (Box 8)
    - Steve Nardella (Box 8)
    - Kafi Patrice Nassoma (Box 8)
    - Native Americans (Box 8)
    - New Detroit Jazz Ensemble (Box 8)
    - The New McKinney's Cotton Pickers (Box 8)
    - John Nicholas (Box 8)
    - Robert Noll (Box 8)
    - Henry Normile (Box 8)
    - Larry Nozer (Box 8)
    - Eddie Nucilli (Box 8)
    - Odetta (Box 8)
    - One String Sam (Box 8)
    - Johnny Otis Show (Box 8)
    - Ozone Parade 1972-1974 (Box 8)
    - Chicago Pete (Box 8)
    - Lucky Peterson 1990 (Box 8)
    - The Persuasions (Box 8)
    - Pioneer Jazz Orchestra (Box 8)
    - Paradise Theater Orchestra (includes Dizzy Gillespie) (Box 8)
    - Parliament Funkadelic (Box 8)
    - Alan Parsons (Box 8)
      (see Clive Davis)
    - The Polish Muslims (Box 8)
    - Jean-Luc Ponty (Box 8)
    - Preservation Hall Jazz Band (Box 8)
    - Prisons (Box 8)
    - Richard Pryor (Box 8)
    - Bonnie Raitt (Box 8)
    - Phil Ranelin (Box 8)
    - Big Red (Box 8)
    - Sonny Redd 1976 (Box 8)
    - Dewey Redman (Box 8)
    - Jimmy Reed (Box 8)
    - Dr. Ross (Box 8)
    - Martha Reeves (Box 8)
    - Reggae (includes Frederick "Toots" Hibbert, Pete Townshend, Peter Tosh, Third World, and Leroy Sibbles) (Box 8)
    - Regular Boys (Box 8)
    - Revolution Ensemble 1970-1973 (Box 8)
    - Rhythm Method/Rhythm Corps (Box 8)
    - Sir Mack Rice (Box 8)
    - Little Richard (Box 8)
    - Sonny Rollins (Box 8)
    - The Roomates (Box 8)
    - Dr. Ross 1971 (Box 8)
    - Dennis Rowland (Box 8)
    - Rob Rudnick (Box 8)
    - Otis Rush (Box 8)
    - Mitch Ryder (Box 8)
    - Ed Sanders (Box 8)
    - Pharoah Sanders (Box 8)
    - Santana (Box 8)
    - Gil Scott-Heron (Box 8)
    - Bob Seger (Box 8)
    - Naima Shambourger (Box 8)
    - Maruga Sharma (Box 8)
    - Archie Shepp 1965-1971 (Box 8)
    - Johnny Shines (Box 8)
    - Shoo-Bee-Doo (Box 8)
    - The Shy 1983-1984 (Box 8)
    - Dave Sinclair (Box 8)
    - John Sinclair, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Larry Smith (Box 8)
    - Leo Smith 1981 (Box 8)
    - Otis and Lucille Spann (Box 8)
    - Danny Spencer (Box 8)
    - The Spinners (Box 8)
    - Victoria Spivey (Box 8)
    - Houston Stackhouse 1973 (Box 8)
    - Strata Musicians (includes Tribe, Bud Spangler, and Kenny Kox) (Box 8)
    - The Sun Messengers (Box 8)
    - Sun Staff (Box 8)
    - Sun-Ra 1970s-1983 (Box 8)
    - David Swain (Box 8)
    - Roosevelt Sykes (Box 8)
    - Grady Tate (Box 8)
    - James Tatum (Box 8)
    - Cecil Taylor (Box 8)
    - Hound Dog Taylor (Box 8)
    - Koko Taylor (Box 8)
    - The Temptations (Box 8)
    - Joe Tex (Box 8)
    - Theatre (Box 8)